A Guide to the Papers of George William Childs, 1889-1892
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of George William Childs 1889-1892
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6819
This collection consists of 45 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library on June 19, 1962.
Scope and Content Information
The papers consist chiefly of letters to Childs in thanks for copies of "Recollections" and "The Stratford Upon Avon Memorial Fountain to Shakespeare." There are very brief mentions of the Philadelphia Public Ledger, the Commercial Bulletin, and Lippincott's Magazine, hopes for fairer treatment of American Indians, U.S. Grant's travels in Grenada and Peking, memorial church windows in London, the common bond between England and the U. S., and portraits of Union generals at West Point.
Arrangement
This collection was arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- George Williams Curtis to George William Childs 1889 Jan 5, TLS, 2 p.
  Thanks for almanac; mentions Public Ledger.
- Hamilton Fish to G. W. C. 1889 Dec 26, ALS, 1 p.
  Thanks for book [ Recollections of General Grant] and inscription of friendship
- Edward John Phelps to G. W. C. 1890 Feb 25, ALS, 3 p.
  Appreciation of book; mentions [Henry] Irving's speech, [Oliver Wendell] Holmes' poem, and [James Russell] Lowell's letter
- [James Willis?] Patterson to G. W. C. 1890 Apr 6, ALS, 1 p.
  Praises G. W. C. 's Recollections; recommends sending a copy to Mrs. Joel B. Erhardt, daughter of Judge Jewett
- Julia D. Grant to G. W. C. 1890 Apr 8, ALS, 2 p.
  Thanks for book and dedication
- Julia D. Grant to G. W. C. 1890 Apr 15, ALS, 3 p.
  Recounts Mrs. Dent's reading his book on Grant to her, and expresses gratitude and praise
- Curtis Guild to G. W. C. 1890 Apr 15, ALS, 2 p.
  Thanks for book on Grant with inscription. Mentions [Oliver Wendell] Holmes, [Thomas Bailey] Aldrich, [Sir Henry Morton] Stanley, [Edwin Percy] Whipple, and [Tom Brown] Hughes. Plans to change size of Commerical Bulletin and write an editorial on G. W. C.'s book.
- Morris Phillips to G. W. C. 1890 Apr 15, ALS, 2 p.
  Thanks for book; will ask son to review it.
- Annie B. Dent to G. W. C. 1890 Apr 15, ALS, 4 p.
  Thanks for book; read it to Mrs. Grant. Recommends it as instructive for men educated at West Point
- Robert Underwood Johnson to G. W. C., ALS, 1 p.
  Thanks for copy of Recollections; sent to Century
- William Winter to L. Clarke Davis 1890 Apr 21, ALS, 1 p.
  Received Child's book. Requests a copy and inscription for the Arthur Winter Memorial Library
- Horace Porter to G. W. C. 1890 Apr 23, ALS, 2 p.
  Received Recollections and sketch of U.S. Grant. Mentions own speech at West Point
- John Habberton to G. W. C. 1890 Apr 25, ALS, 1 p.
  Thanks for Recollections and inscription
- Edward Dow Giffin Prime to G. W. C. 1890 Apr 30, ALS, 2 p.
  Thanks for book; will send volume of Family Records
- Hamilton Fish to G. W. C. 1890 May 3, ALS, 1 p.
  Thanks and praise for book
- Henry Coppee to G. W. C. 1890 May 7, ALS, 2 p.
  Thanks for book and inscription
- Ellen M. Hutchinson to G. W. C. 1890 May 9, ALS, 3 p.
  Thanks and appreciation for book
- Annie Fields to G. W. C. 1890 May 20, ALS, 2 p.
  Thanks for book. Refers to treatment of the Indians
- William E. Curtis to G. W. C. 1890 May 22, ALS, 2 p.
  Thanks for book and inscription; had read it in article form in [ Lippincott's] Magazine
- Elizabeth C. Agassiz to G. W. C. 1890 Jun 12, ALS, 1 p.
  Thanks for book
- Reverdy Johnson to G. W. C. 1890 Jun 18, ALS, 2 p.
- George W. Knight to G. W. C. 1890 Jun 23, ALS, 4 p.
  Praises Recollections and U.S. Grant. Refers to presentation of portraits of three Union generals to West Point. Mentions Shakespeare Fountain at Stratford, memorial windows at Westminster and St. Margaret's, and childhood in Oxford. Discusses common bond between America and England.
- James R. Young to G. W. C. 1890 Jun 23, ALS, 1 p.
- Lucy H. Hooper to G. W. C. [1890] Aug 29, ALS, 2 p.
  Thanks for book on the Shakespeare Fountain at Stratford, and notice of Mr. Hooper in Public Ledger.
- A. E. Edwards to G. W. C. 1890 Aug 12
  Thanks for "The Story of the Memorial Fountain to Shakespeare"
- Oliver Wendell Holmes to G. W. C. 1890 Aug 22, ALS, 1 p.
  Thanks and praise for book and inscription
- Jesse Seligman to G. W. C. 1890 Sep 8, ALS, 3 p.
- Mary Astor to G. W. C. [1890] Sep 14, ALS, 3 p.
  Thanks for book on Shakespeare Fountain
- William Waldorf Astor to G. W. C. 1890 Sep 16, ALS, 1 p.
  Thanks for copy and praise of Recollections
- "Grace Greenwood" [Sara Jane Lippincott] to G. W. C. 1890 Oct 6, ALS, 4 p.
  Refers to her tribute [to G. W. C. ?] and to work on juvenile books; asks that her books be given notice in the Ledger. Mentions J. G. Whittier and Hawthorne
- M. H. Allibone to G. W. C. 1890 Dec 2, ALS, 2 p.
  Thanks for book. Mentions Mr. Whitacker, Lippincott's Magazine, Dr. McConnell, and Hasty [Pudding?] Society
- Madeleine Vinton Dahlgren to G. W. C. 1891 [Mar 19], ALS, 3 p.
  Thanks for book and inscription. Mentions Lippincott's Magazine and comments on his relations with employees.
- Edward John Phelps to G. W. C. 1891 Apr 2, ALS, 2 p.
  Thanks and praise for Recollections. Mentions [ Public] Ledger.
- Patrick John Ryan to G. W. C. 1891 Apr 5, ALS, 1 p.
  Praise for Recollections.
- Henry Codman Potter to G.W.C. 1891 Apr 6, ALS, 4 p.
  Requests copy of new edition of Recollections and praises G. W. C. for furthering cause of international brotherhood.
- James Parton to G. W. C. 1891 Apr 10, ALS, 4 p.
  Approves of Child's attitude toward employees; mentions [ Public Ledger]
- Hamilton Fish to G. W. C. 1891 Apr 18, ALS, 1 p.
  Pleased that another edition of Recollections is to be published.
- Oliver Wendell Holmes to G. W. C. 1891 Apr 19, ALS, 2 p.
  Comments on G. W. C.'s book and praises his career.
- John Russell Gary to G. W. C. 1891 Apr 30, ALS, 3 p.
  Thanks for book; mentions U. S. Grant in Grenada, and some ivory sent to G. W. C. Mentions Peking and the theft of an ivory cup.
- John Greenleaf Whittier to G. W. C. 1891 May 1, ALS, 2 p.
  Praises G. W. C.
- James Gibbons to G. W. C. 1891 May 15, ALS, 2 p.
  Praises Recollections
- Richard Watson Gilder to 1891 Jun 1, ALS, 1 p.
  Praises G. W. C. to correspondent.
- Theodore L[edyard] Cuyler to G. W. C. 1891 Jun 25, ALS, 2 p.
  Suggests enlarged edition of Recollections. Mentions Benjamin Franklin and "Sam Weller."
- Mary D. Harrison to G. W. C. 1892 Jan 31, ALS, 4 p.
- A. G. Curtin to G. W. C. 1892 Mar 19, ALS, 1 p.
  Thanks for copy of Recollections